Sawyer Pearson

Boise, ID | 208-284-2019 | sawyer.pearson208@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/sawyer-pearson Portfolio: https://www.sawyer-pearson.com/

Full Stack Web Developer

Ambitious web developer with a passion for creating powerful, intuitive web sites & web-based tools. Six years of experience in eCommerce combining work ethic, technical skill & desire for growth to automate repetitive tasks, and create impactful content to drive customer traffic.

Skill

- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript
- Wireframes
- Photoshop
- WordPress
- Responsive Design
- Node.js with Knex
- SQL
- Python
- Postgres
- Heroku
- Supertest

- Agile Methodologies
- SEO
- Jira & Trello
- Customer Service
- Version Control
- Effective remote work

Experience

eCommerce Content Specialist | Bodybuilding.com - Boise, ID | Oct 2015 – Oct 2020 Primary roles included building responsive custom product pages from vendor supplied PSDs, updating marketing landing pages, assisting with automation & updating styling sheets.

Technical Support Specialist | CommentSold - Remote | Feb 2021 – Present Primary roles include diagnosing & resolving technical issues customers have with our software, updating documentation & communicating issues across various departments.

Achievements

- Can Tool: Created the front & back end for a customer service tool designed to improve efficiency by allowing representatives to create and store custom templated replies they can copy/paste through a chat platform.
- **Sku Onboarding Automation:** Worked closely with a small team to decrease sku onboarding time by **58%** for select projects. This primarily involved the use of gsheets to transfer data from vendors directly into our sku management system as opposed to using a manual data entry method.
- **Ingredient Parsing Tool:** Created a lightweight app to strip ingredients off nutritional labels and assort them into an itemized list. This facilitated faster & more accurate entry of nutritional information on supplement panels.

Education

Full Stack Web Development | Lambda School | March 2020 – Jan 2021 **Bachelor of Science** – *Human Biology* | Boise State University | 2010 – 2014